PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hard-working and multi-talented professional with strong skills tied with natural sciences, computer science, and team leadership. With years of work and educational experience honing my abilities, I have input for: AWS cloud development, native species research, public health protection, environmental restoration, data input, and multiple coding languages including: Python, Matlab, SQL, and C++.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

- AWS cloud development, web-site and application development and deployment, cloud infrastructure implementation, and cloud computing
- Data input and Microsoft Office suite experience and proficiency.
- Team and self management in office and field environments.
- Excels in problem solving and learning new systems.

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Udemy Certificate for Python
- Microsoft Office suite proficient
- Data entry with 60 WPM typing speed
- Wet and Dry lab techniques
- Light Microscopy
- Biological Transect Survey and Data Collection
- Geologic and construction field Survey
- Field Data Correlation and mapping

EXPERIENCE

Restoration Technician/Crew Leader (40 hrs/week)

Dec 2021-Present

Prunuske Chatham Inc, Sebastopol, CA | Rick Kaye: (707)527-2994

- Working on or leading a crew in native landscape construction, restoration, and implementation, running a wide array of equipment.
- Assisting on field survey crews, gathering land survey data.
- Working individually outside of the county without direct support from a crew, requiring a strong work ethic, careful planning, and the ability to solve problems faced in the field.

Teller and Security Worker (0-20+ hrs/week, Seasonal)

Feb 2017-Oct 2022

Petaluma Pumpkin Patch, Petaluma, CA | James Groverman: (707)481-7663

Assistant Carpenter (40 hrs/week)

Nov 2018-Dec 2021

Rusty Mila Construction, Santa Rosa, CA | Rusty Mila: (707)326-0573

• This job allowed me to return to college, and supported me through the pandemic.

Field Assistant (40 hrs/week)

March 2018-Oct 2018

Marin/Sonoma Mosquito & Vector Control District, Cotati, CA | Jason Sequeira: (707)285-2200

Fisheries Technician I (20-40 hrs/week)

March 2017-Dec 2017

Pacific States Marine Fisheries Commission, Santa Rosa, CA | Barry Miller: (707)576-2860

Ranch Manager/Assistant (20+ hrs/week)

Aug 2011-June 2014

Groverman Shropshires, Petaluma, CA | Fred Groverman: Deceased

Mathematics Tutor (10 hrs/week)

Aug 2013-May 2014

Mathematics Lab, Santa Rosa Junior College | Debra Miller: (707)524-1657

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts: Marine Science

Dec 2016

University of California, Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

Associate in Arts: Mathematics (Highest Honors)

May 2014

Santa Rosa Junior College

Santa Rosa, CA

WEBSITES

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-fessler/

Github Profile: https://github.com/jffessler